<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Golem</name>
		<description></description>
	    <update version="1.0">
			<file name="race-Golem.xml" url=""/>
		</update>
	</info>

  <element name="Golem" type="Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HMBRW_RACE_GOLEM">
    <description>
      <h4>Golem</h4>
      <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Constitution increases by 2, and one other ability score increases by 1.<br/>
      <span class="feature">Age.</span>Golems are not born as mortals are, and they do not age as mortals do. They are constructed, so your character's age is based upon when you were created or emerged from the wild.<br/>
	<span class="feature">Alignment</span>Golems, especially inorganic golems, are programmed to carry out the will of their creators. Therefore, they tend toward lawful alignments.<br/>
      <span class="feature">Size.</span>The most powerful golems, particularly those constructed by legendary artificers or born of fabled, magical sources, may tower above mortals. However, most appear a bit taller than most humans.<br/>
      <span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br/>
      <span class="feature">Hibernation Mode</span>When you take a long rest, you do not sleep. Instead, you must spend at least six hours in an inactive motionless state. In this state, you appear inert, but it does not render you unconscious. You continue to see and hear with Disadvantage to your Perception checks. You also don't need to eat or drink, and you are immune to poison.<br/>
	<span class="feature">Designed for battles of death</span>Because of the natural reason that golems are used they are built to be more advanced on their physical side. While creating your character you may choose up to 2 skill points to remove from intelligence and add to either constitution or strength.<br/>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false"/>
    <rules>
      <stat name="constitution" value="2"/>
      <stat name="any" value="1"/>
      <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
      <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_VA-NOX" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HMBRW_RACIAL_TRAIT_GOLEM_HIBERNATION MODE" />
	<grant type"Racial Trait" id="ID_HMBRW_RACIAL_TRAIT_GOLEM_DESIGNED FOR DEATH" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  
   <element name="Hibernation Mode" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HMBRW_RACIAL_TRAIT_GOLEM_HIBERNATION MODE">
    <description>
			<p> When you take a long rest, you do not sleep. Instead, you must spend at least six hours in an inactive motionless state. In this state, you appear inert, but it does not render you unconscious. You continue to see and hear with Disadvantage to your Perception checks. You also don't need to eat or drink, and you are immune to poison.</p>
		</description>
  </element>
<element name="Designed for battles of death" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HMBRW_RACIAL_TRAIT_GOLEM_DESIGNED FOR DEATH">
	<description> 
			<p> because of the natural reason that golems are used they are built to be more advanced on their physical side. While creating your character you may choose up to 2 skill points to remove from intelligence and add to either constitution or strength.</p>
	</description>
</element>
</elements>
